Lucas Petherbridge

Senior Software Engineer

Passionate & driven polyglot software engineer with 8+ years of experience solving problems. Started programming at age 15 and have consistently sought to expand and grow. Great communicator and team collaborator willing to take on any challenge.

Personal Info

Address

9826 SW 59th Ave Portland, OR 97219

Phone

(503) 616-8265

Email

me@lukeworks.tech

Website

https://lukeworks.tech/

Languages & **Technologies**

- Javascript; React; Angular;
- Rust; C; C++; Golang
- Python; Perl; Bash
- · GraphQL; Apache; Ngnix; MySQL; PostgreSQL
- AWS; Docker; Kubernetes; Jenkins; Terraform

Employment



Senior Software Engineer

TEKsystems - Consultant at Nike, Beaverton, OR Mar 2020 - Jul 2020 · 4 mos

- Extended a product planning tool that enabled Merchant and Product teams to plan future product lines using JavaScript, Angular, Node.js, Typescript, GraphQL, & MySQL.
- Designed, configured, & set up cloud infrastructure as code for a GraphQL API using Okta authentication, AWS & Terraform.
- Created & managed CI/CD pipelines using Github, AWS CLI, BMX Jenkins & Docker.
- Led team in clarifying scope, technology & architecture decisions for a new merchant planning project.
- Mentored, provided code reviews & pair programmed with junior developers.
- Exit: Contract ended due to organization restructure.



Senior Software Engineer

NetFortris (Formerly Fonality, Inc), Culver City, CA Nov 2013 - Mar 2020 · 6 yrs 5 mos

- Worked remotely for 6 years while maintaining high productivity & close collaboration with teams.
- Extended mobile UCaaS application to enable a rich customer integration experience using React Native & Redux with
- Redesigned Salesforce integration using modern APIs on a solo project reducing project size by 90% by switching from Angular to Vue.js thus increasing maintainability using JavaScript, Vue.js, XML, & Apex.
- Developed & integrated a flexible cloud platform for a UCaaS system to achieve high scalability & availability using Perl & Golang.
- Reduced dependency on legacy systems by 80% by developing a fault tolerant & automated migration which led to a 15% reduction in support & billing costs.
- Designed & developed an OSS/BSS for the ordering, billing, & provisioning of telephony services that led to a 20% increase in revenue using Perl, JavaScript, JQuery, & HTML/CSS.

Education



Bachelor of Computer Science

Portland State University, Portland, OR 2015 - 2019

 Consulted as a Scrum/Agile coach for 10 teams during my senior capstone in lieu of a project, providing guidance & support in the completion of their team projects.

Technical Experience

Projects

- TetaNES (Mar '19 Current). A Nintendo Entertainment System (NES) cross-platform/web emulator written in Rust using SDL2 & WebAssembly. (https://github.com/lukexor/tetanes)
- Personal Portfolio/Blog (Aug '14 Current). A website for blog articles & projects using Python, Django, Nginx, MySQL, & Redis. Currently working on a new version using React, GraphQL, Rust, & Rocket. (https://lukeworks.tech/)
- Miscellaneous. Various side projects and other coding exercises including a suite of visual programs showcasing algorithms, animations, & game physics using the p5.js Javascript library & HTML5 canvas. (https://lukeworks.tech/projects/)